- What's all this fuss about, Charters?
- Damned if I know.
Ladies and gentlemen, train is uphold
and if you wish to stay in my hotel...
you will have
to register immediately.
Why the deuce didn't he say
so in the first place?
How do you do ladies. It's a great
honour to have you with us again.
It's nice to see you, Boris. You
haven't changed a bit since Friday.
- I see you haven't shaved.
- Is everything ready?
- Everything. I didn't change anything.
- Not even the sheets? Lead on.
I didn't expect
you to come so quickly.
Our legs gave out. We had to do
the last lap in a farm cart.
We've company. Don't tell me Cook's
are running cheap tours here.
- What is it, Boris?
- The havelunch!
- Have a lunch?
- Avalanche, Boris.
In spring you've many avalanches. The
snow go boom! Everything disappears.
Even trains disappear
under the avalanche.
But I'm going home tomorrow.
How long before they dig it out?
By morning. It's lucky you
can leave by this train.
How do you say? It's a bad wind
that blow nowhere no good.
We haven't
eaten since dawn.
Serve us some supper,
in our rooms.
- I could eat a horse.
- Don't put ideas in his head.
Some chicken, Boris.
And a magnum of champagne.
And make it snappy.
Bandrika may have a dictator but
tonight we're painting it red.
Meanwhile we are here cooling
our heels. What impudence!
- 3rd rate country. What do you expect?
- I wonder who those women are.
Probably Americans.
Almighty dollar.
We'll have to wait. If only we
hadn't missed that train at Budapest.
But you insisted on standing till they
finished their National Anthem...
You must show respect. If I knew
it was going to last 20 minutes...
It's my contention that the Hungarian
Rhapsody is not their National Anthem.
- We were the only two standing.
- That's true.
I suppose we shall be
in time after all.
That last report was pretty ghastly.
England on the brink.
Newspaper sensationalism. The old
country's been in tight corners before.
Looks pretty black. Even if
we leave first thing in the morning...
there's still a connection at Basle.
We'll probably be hours.
- That's true.
- Somebody surely can help us.
Sir! Do you know what time
the train leaves Basle for England?
Really! Fellow doesn't
speak English.
Here's one leaves Basle, 21:20.
There is only two single rooms in
front, or a double room at the back.
- We'll take the two single rooms.
- Very well, sir.
- You might have asked me.
- A small double room in this place...
You weren't so particular
in Paris in Autumn.
That was different.
The Exhibition was at its height.
I realise that.
There's no need to rub it in.
- A private suite with a bath.
- Facing the mountains.
- With a shower.
- Hot and cold.
- And a private thingummy.
- We've only got the maid's room!
- What's this?
- I'm sorry.
- The whole hotel is packed.
- We haven't fixed up yet.
You can't expect the two
of us to sleep in the maid's room.
Don't get excited.
I'll move the maid out.
I should think so. What?
What are you taking about.
I'll sleep on the train.
- There is no eating in the train.
- No eating?
Heating...
That's awkward.
All right we'll take it.
One condition. The maid
has to come to your room...
to remove her wardrobe.
Anna!
She's a good girl,
and I don't want to lose her.
We'd better go and dress.
- Rather primitive humour, I thought.
- Grown up children.
That was an awkward
situation, over that girl.
Pity he couldn't have given us
one each. I mean a room apiece.
I, Iris Matilda Henderson,
a spinster of no particular parish...
solemnly renounce my maidenly past
and declare that on Thursday 26...
I shall take the veil and
orange blossom...
and change my name to
Lady Charles Fotheringail.
- Can't he change his name?
- I only like his moustache.
You're cynics.
I'm very fond of him.
I'm fond of rabbits but they
have to be kept down.
Rudolph, give me a hand.
- Do you know that thing called love?
- It used to be very popular.
The carpet is already laid at
St. Georges, Hanover Square...
and Father is aching to have
a coat of arms on the jam label.
To Iris, and the happy days
she's leaving behind.
And the blue blooded cheque chaser
she's dashing to London to marry.
The blue blooded
cheque chaser.
I've no regrets. I've been everywhere
and done everything.
I've eaten caviar at Cannes,
sausage rolls at the dogs.
I've played baccarat at Biarritz
and darts with the rural dean.
What is there left
for me but marriage?
Mustn't lose grip, Charters.
Come in.
- Did you follow that?
- Tell her this has gone far enough.
No... no.
Change... here. Outside.
- She doesn't understand.
- No, come on.
- Nothing newer than last month.
- And no wireless set here.
Awful being in the dark like this.
Communications cut off in a crisis.
Hello, hello, London.
You want Mr Seltzer? Yes hold on.
I'm going to find where he is.
London!
Go on, risk it.
Hello... You... in London. No, I'm not
Mr Seltzer. Name's Charters.
I don't suppose you know me. Don't
worry. They've gone to fetch him.
Tell me, what's
happening to England?
Blowing a gale? No, I'm inquiring
about the test match in Manchester.
Cricket, sir. Cricket!
You don't know?
You can't be in England
and not know the test score.
The fellow says he doesn't know.
Hello, can't you find out?
It won't take a second.
All right, if you won't, you won't.
The fellow's an ignoramus.
Mr Seltzer, at last your call's
come through to London.
Hello! Hello!
Thank you, waiter.
- What about a grilled steak?
- Good idea.
- Well done for me, please.
- On the red side for me.
These people have a passion
for repeating themselves.
I beg your pardon.
He's trying to explain that due to the
number of visitors, there's no food.
No food? What sort of a place is this?
They expect us to share a dog box...
with a servant on an empty stomach?
Is that hospitality and organisation?
Thank you.
- I'm hungry.
- No wonder they have revolutions.
You're welcome to the cheese. It's
not steak but it's rich in vitamins.
Thank you.
We're not accustomed to
catering to so many people.
Bandrika is one of
Europe's undiscovered corners.
Perhaps there's nothing
to discover.
You may not know it as well as me.
Leaving makes me quite miserable.
- After you with that cheese, please!
- Certainly. You're going home?
Tomorrow. My charges are grown up.
I'm a governess and a music teacher.
In the 6 years that I've lived here,
I've grown to love it.
Especially the mountains. I think that
they are like very friendly neighbours.
The father and mother mountains
with their white snow hats...
and their nephews and
nieces, with smaller hats.
Right down to their tiniest hillock
without any hat at all.
- Of course, that's just my fancy.
- Really?
I like to watch them from my bedroom
every night when there's a moon.
I'm so glad there's a moon tonight.
Do you hear that music?
Everyone sings here. The people are
just like happy children...
with laughter on their lips
and music in their hearts.
It's not reflected in their politics.
You shouldn't judge
any country by its politics.
We English are quite honest by
nature. You'll excuse me if I run away?
- Good night, good night.
- Good night.
Queer sort of bird.
- Trifle whimsical, I thought.
- After 6 years, we'd be whimsical.
I don't think so. She was very decent
about that cheese.
I see she's finished
the pickles.
Good night, Iris. Listen,
someone's serenading.
Let him. Nothing will keep me
awake tonight. Good night.
- What's happening? An earthquake?
- That wouldn't account for the music.
- What a noise. What can they be doing?
- I don't know but I'll soon find out.
Hello.
Musical country this.
I feel quite sorry for that poor singer
outside having to compete with this.
Boris?
Miss Henderson speaking.
Someone upstairs is playing
musical chairs with an elephant.
Move one of them out.
I need to sleep.
- That'll settle it.
- Thank you.
Some people have no consideration,
which makes life more difficult.
Don't you think?
Good night.
You'll be going back
in the morning?
I hope we shall meet again
under quieter circumstances.
- Good night.
Miss, please,
I'll fix everything.
You'd better.
Hold it.
Splendid, don't move.
- If you please, sir.
- Get out!
One, two.
Please, sir,
will you kindly stop?
They are all complaining in the whole
hotel. You make too much noise.
- Too much what?
- Too much noise.
You dare to call it noise.
The ancient music...
with which your ancestors celebrated
every wedd for countless generations.
What they danced when your
father married your mother...
if you were born in wedlock,
which I doubt. Look at them.
- You are the manager?
- Sure...
I am accustomed to squalor.
Who's complaining?
The young English
lady underneath.
Tell her that I am putting on record
for the benefit of mankind...
one of the lost folk dances
of Central Europe...
and she does not own
the hotel. Get out!
Now, one, two...
He said: "Is she the Queen of Sheeba?
She thinks she owns the hotel."
- Can't you get rid of him?
- Impossible.
Are you sure?
I begin to wonder...
It's coming back to me.
I have got an idea.
The German lady
will call him and say:
"It is my room. I did pay for it.
Get out quickly." How's that?
Good enough.
We will inject him with a little... He'll
never forget as long as he lives.
Nothing but baseball. Children play
it with a rubber ball and a stick.
Not a word about cricket.
Americans have
no sense of proportion.
Come in.
Can't stand this ridiculous
lack of privacy. Lock the door.
Who are you?
What do you want?
- Recognise the signature tune?
- Will you please get out?
This is a much better room.
Definitely an acceptable room.
What exactly do you think you're
doing? Keep away!
Would you hold these
for a minute?
Put those back at once.
- Which side do you like to sleep?
- Do you want me to throw you out?
In that case,
I'll sleep in the middle.
Smart of you
to bribe the manager.
An eye for an eye and a tooth
for a toothbrush.
- You're behaving like a complete cad.
- You're at liberty to sleep in the corridor.
Hello.
I shouldn't if I were you. I'd only
tell everyone you invited me here.
And when I say everyone, I mean
everyone. I have a powerful voice.
Come out of there at once!
Not until you bribe the manager
to restore me to my attic.
Come out!
Boris? I might change
my mind about the room upstairs.
Have my things
taken upstairs, will you?
You're the most contemptible person
I've ever met in my life!
I think you're a bit
of a stinker, too.
If we get to Basle in time,
we should see the match.
Hope the weather's like this in
Manchester. Perfect for cricket.
Isn't it somewhere along here?
If you don't hurry, Margaret, we shan't
get that compartment to ourselves.
Does it matter?
There's time
to change your mind.
Send Charles a telegram
and tell him he's all washed up.
This time next week, I shall be a
slightly sunburnt offering on an altar.
I shan't mind, really.
Good morning. I can't find my bag.
It's a brown hold-all.
Have you seen it?
No, of course not, thank you.
She's dropped her glasses.
- You dropped your glasses.
- Thank you...
Oh dear! Oh dear!
- Are you hurt?
- I don't know. What was it?
Never mind. This cockeyed station
has practically brained my friend.
- Yes, indeed.
- What are you going to do?
- He can't hold the train.
- I like that!
- Hurry up. It's going.
- I'm all right.
- Are you sure?
- Don't worry...
I'll look after her.
Such carelessness.
- Are you sure you're all right?
- Send us the Times.
- Write and tell us all about it.
- Good luck. Look after yourself.
You'll be all right in a minute.
Just take everything quietly.
Put this eau de cologne
on your head.
- Do you feel any better?
- Yes, thank you. I'm all right.
What you need is a good strong cup
of tea. I'll ring for the attendant.
No, please, don't bother. I'll go to the
dining car myself. I need some air.
- I'll come with you, if you don't mind.
- No, of course not.
I beg your pardon.
I'm so sorry.
You can always tell a honeymoon
couple. They're so shy.
- Why did you do that?
- We don't want people staring.
You'd think the whole legal
profession was after you.
One would be enough.
You thought that beggar in
Damascus was a barrister.
I just said he looked like
a judge.
You hurried off
in the opposite direction.
That's not true. I was looking
for a street called "Straight".
- You weren't so careful at first.
- I know.
And what about me? Robert thinks
I'm cruising with Mother.
If one is feeling shaky, it's best to
sit in the middle of the coach...
facing the engine.
- A pot of tea, please.
- Very good.
And just a minute.
Will you please tell them to make it
from this? I don't drink any other.
And make sure the water is
really boiling. Do you understand?
It's a little fad of mine. My dear father
and mother, who are still alive...
and enjoying good health, drink it
and so I follow their footsteps.
A million Mexicans drink it. At least
that's what it says on the packet.
It's very kind of you
to help me.
I don't think
we've introduced ourselves.
My name's Iris Henderson,
I'm going home to be married.
How very exciting.
I do hope you'll be happy.
- Thank you.
- You'll have children, won't you?
They make such a difference. I always
think it's being with kiddies so much...
that's made me so young for my age.
I'm a governess. My name's Froy.
- Did you say Freud?
- No. O-Y, not E-U-D. Froy.
I'm sorry I can't hear.
Froy. It rhymes with joy.
Thank you. Please reserve two places
for lunch, if you'd care to join me.
It wasn't out. But for the umpire's
blunder he'd still be batting.
- What do you mean?
- I'll show you. I saw the whole thing.
There's Hammond, there's the bowler,
and there's the umpire.
- Sugar?
- Two please.
Dear me.
There's no sugar.
Now watch this very carefully.
Grimmett was bowling.
- May I trouble you for the sugar?
- What?
The sugar, please.
Thank you so much.
I'd try to get a little sleep,
it'll make you feel quite well.
There's a most intriguing acrostic
in the "Needlewoman".
I'm going to try and
unravel it before you wake up.
Reservations for lunch, please.
- Madame has booked for lunch?
- My friend did. She's got the tickets.
Have you seen my friend?
My friend, where is she?
La signora inglese.
The English lady.
There has been no
English lady here.
What?
There has been
no English lady here.
But there has.
She sat there in the corner.
You saw her, you spoke to her,
she sat next to you.
Is ridiculous. She took
me to the dining car...
- and came back here with me.
- You went and came back alone.
Maybe you don't understand.
The lady who looked after
me when I was knocked out.
Perhaps it make you forget?
If this is some sort of a joke
I'm afraid I don't see the point.
- You served me tea just now.
- Yes, Madame.
- Have you seen the lady I was with?
- But Madame was alone.
Pardon, Madame.
He make mistake.
He must remember the English lady.
She ordered tea and paid for it.
No, it was you
who paid for it.
He says to look
at the bill. I will look.
She gave you a special
packet of tea.
The tea was ours.
I received no packet.
- But you did. I know it happened.
- Pardon, the bill. Tea for one.
But that's not right.
- Would you care to examine the bills?
- No. The whole thing's absurd.
Please, have you seen
a lady pass through?
Old Stinker! If I thought
you were on this train...
I'd have stayed a week
at the hotel. Lady? No, why?
It doesn't matter. You probably
wouldn't recognise one anyway.
- Hello! Feeling queer?
- It's that pipe of yours, George.
Why don't you throw your old socks
away? Thanks for the help.
Come on, sit down.
What's the trouble?
- Something fell on my head.
- When? Infancy?
- At the station.
- Bad luck! Can I help?
No, only by going away.
My father taught me
not to dessert a lady in trouble.
He even married mother.
Did you see a little lady last night
in the hotel in tweeds?
I saw one but she
was hardly in tweeds.
She was with me,
and now I can't find her.
She must still be on the train.
We haven't stopped.
- Of course she is.
- All right. Nobody said she isn't.
- But that's what they say.
- Who?
The people in the compartment
and the steward.
They insist they never saw her.
All of them.
- You said you got a knock on the head.
- What do you mean?
- Never mind. Do you talk the lingo?
- No.
Maybe they thought you tried
to borrow money.
Let's knock the idea out of their
heads. A most unfortunate remark.
That's one of them.
The little dark man.
There is a misunderstanding. This
lady seems to have lost her friend.
Yes, I have heard. The gentleman
has been explaining to me.
I think under the circumstances
we shall introduce ourselves.
I am an Italian citizen.
My wife and child.
How do you do. Bonny little chap.
How old is he?
1934 class.
And the lady in the corner
is the Baroness Athona.
I met her husband, he presented
prizes at the Folk Dances Festival.
Minister of Propaganda.
I am Dr Egon Hartz of Prague.
You may have heard of me.
- Not the brain specialist?
- The same.
You went to England to operate
on one of our cabinet ministers.
- Yes.
- Did you find anything?
- A slight cerebral contusion.
- That's better than nothing.
I am picking up a similar case at the
next station, but more complicated.
I shall operate at the
National Hospital tonight.
Among other things a cranial fracture
with completion. You understand?
- Yes, a wallop on the bean.
- I suppose you haven't seen my friend?
- Unfortunately no.
- I'll take a word with the Baroness.
- What do they say?
- Both say they've never seen her.
That's not true.
She was sitting there.
- Can you describe her?
- It's difficult.
- She was middle-aged and ordinary.
- What was she wearing?
Tweeds, oatmeal flecked with brown,
a coat with patch pockets...
a scarf, felt hat, brown shoes,
a tussle shirt...
and a small blue handkerchief in her
breast pocket. I can't remember.
You could've been paying attention.
You both went along to tea?
- Yes.
- Surely you met somebody.
Right you are.
Now let's dig him out.
Pardon. May I come with you?
This is most interesting.
We don't like people muscling in,
but we'll make you a member.
Wait. There was somebody else.
As we passed this compartment...
Miss Froy stumbled in and there
was a tall gentleman and a lady.
If we can really find someone
who saw her...
we'll have
the place searched.
- Can I be of any assistance?
- That's the gentleman.
Do you remember seeing this young lady
pass with a little English woman?
I'm afraid not.
You must! She almost fell
into your compartment.
Surely you haven't forgotten.
It's very important.
Everybody's saying she wasn't here,
but I'm going to find her...
even if
I have to stop the train.
Caldicott, it's Charters.
Can I come in?
That girl we saw in the hotel,
she's kicking up a fuss.
- Says she lost her friend.
- She hasn't been in here, old man.
- She's threatening to stop the train.
- Lord!
If we miss our connection in Basle,
we'll never make Manchester in time.
- This is serious.
- Let's hide in here.
I haven't the faintest recollection.
You must be making a mistake.
He obviously doesn't remember.
Let's look for the other fellow.
- Who were you talking to outside?
- People in the corridor, arguing.
- There he is. That's the man.
- I wonder if you can help us.
- How?
- I was having tea an hour ago...
with an English lady.
You saw her, didn't you?
- I was talking to my friend.
- Indubitably.
Yes, but you were at the next table.
She borrowed the sugar.
- I recall passing the sugar.
- Then you saw her.
We were in deep conversation,
discussing cricket.
How a thing like cricket
can make you forget seeing people?
If that's your attitude,
there's nothing more to say.
Come, Caldicott.
Thing like cricket.
Wrong tactic. We should have told him
we were looking for a cricket ball.
Yes, but he spoke to her.
There must be some explanation.
There is.
Please forgive me.
I'm quite possibly wrong
but I have known cases...
when a sudden shock or blow has
induced the most vivid impressions.
- I understand. You don't believe me.
- It's not a question of belief.
Even a concussion may have curious
effects upon an imaginative person.
I can remember every little detail.
Her name. Miss Froy. Everything.
So interesting.
If one had time...
one could trace the cause
of the hallucination.
- Hallucination?
- Precisely. There is no Miss Froy.
- Just a vivid subjective image.
- But I met her last night at the hotel.
- You thought you did.
- What about her name?
A past association. An advertisement,
a character subconsciously remembered.
No, there is no reason to be afraid,
if you are quiet and relaxed.
Thank you very much.
Dravake. If you will excuse me, this
is where my patient comes aboard.
Excuse me.
Most interesting.
We're stopping.
This is our first stop, isn't it?
Miss Froy must still be on the train.
You look out this window
and see if she gets off this side.
I'll take the other.
Most interesting.
What was she dressed in?
Scotch tweeds, wasn't it?
- Oatmeal tweeds.
- I knew it had to do with porridge.
How long does it take
to get a divorce?
- Eric?
- I'm sorry. I wasn't listening.
How long does it take
to get a divorce?
That depends. Why?
I was wondering if we could take
our honey moon next spring.
The official one.
The difficulties are considerable.
The courts are very crowded now.
I suppose we barristers
ought not to complain about this.
With conditions as they are now, my
chances of becoming a judge are rosy.
- That is, if nothing untoward occurs.
- Like being mixed up in a divorce?
In the first careless rapture of yours
you didn't care what happened.
The law, like Caesar's wife,
must be above all suspicion.
Even when the law spends six
weeks with Caesar's wife?
I know why you are running around
like a scared rabbit...
- and why lied so elaborately just now.
- I lied?
Yes, to those people in the corridor.
I heard every word you said.
I didn't wish to be
mixed up in an enquiry.
Enquiry? Just because a little
woman can't be found?
That girl was making a fuss.
If the woman had disappeared...
and I'd admitted to seeing her, we
might have become vital witnesses.
My name might appear
in the papers with yours.
A scandal that might
lead anywhere, anywhere.
Yes, I suppose
you are right.
- Nobody?
- Nobody.
I just saw bits of orange peel
and paper bag coming out my side.
I know there's a Miss Froy.
She's as real as you are.
That's what you
say and you believe it.
But there isn't anybody else
who has seen her.
- I saw her. I think.
- You did?
- A little woman in tweeds.
- Yes.
- With a three quarter coat.
- With a scarf.
That's right. I saw her when
you passed the compartment.
I knew I was right. But your husband
said he didn't see her.
He didn't notice, but as soon as he
mentioned it, I remembered at once.
You win. This calls for action.
Would you make a statement?
Of course, if it helps.
Pardon, my patient has just arrived.
The most fascinating complication.
We have news for you.
This lady saw Mrs. Froy.
- So.
- We are going to search the train.
- You must think of a fresh theory.
- It is not necessary.
My theory was perfectly good.
The facts were misleading.
I hope you will find
your friend.
- I'll be right here if you want me.
- OK. Come along.
I was going to mention that
I told that girl I'd seen her friend.
- Have you taken leave of your senses?
- On the contrary, I've come to them.
What do you mean?
If there is a scandal, there'll be
a divorce. You couldn't let me down.
You'd have to do the decent thing
as only you know how.